Jonathan Westman

Front-end Web Developer

Mobile: (909)913-0208 • Home: (909)255-1637

http://westmaninteractive.com • info@westmaninteractive.com

Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web projects, I possess a Bachelor's of Science in Web Design and Interactive Media and have over 5 years building and maintaining websites for enterprise level clients. I seek to secure a position as a Front-end Developer where I can utilize my skills as well as an opportunity to continue to grow as a web developer.

SKILLS

Agile/Scrum, Angular, CSS3, CSS Preprocessors, CSS Frameworks, Drupal, Git, HTML5, Javascript, jQuery, Mustache, PHP, Java, XML, YAML, Unix/Linux CLI

WORK EXPERIENCE

ActiveLAMP, Victorville, CA - Front-end Developer

August 2013 - Present

Responsibilities:

- Project lead for large non-profit client.
- Maintained and updated multiple client projects within Drupal
- Performed tasks in a scrum/agile manner working within a team to complete tasks in a given sprint
- Used git and CI services to manage projects, code reviews and deployments
- Used project management tools such as JIRA/Confluence to manage projects, track progress and keep documentation
- Used MySQL to collect data and migrate content from one environment to another, writing scripts to handle this process as well as running sql statements directly on local databases
- Set up and used SCSS Lint to keep our SCSS within recommended and set guidelines
- Worked with remote workers to complete tasks on the project and made sure that all items get accomplished
- Used XDebug to step through processes to debug specific functionality of the site
- Wrote visual regression test cases using shoov.io using Javascript, graphicsmagick, and webdrivercss
- Wrote blog posts for company site and created video tutorial for company Youtube
- Helped write and code review our QA's tests using SauceLabs Sausage
- Experience with large cloud-based hosting platforms such as Acquia, Pantheon, Heroku, Platform.sh, and Amazon Services

 Learned Drupal 8 Development practices including twig, yaml, Drush, Drupal Console, and template inheritance

Saavedra Designs, Hesperia, CA - Freelance Developer

December 2011 - January 2016

Responsibilities:

- Developed Wordpress websites focusing on modularity and client usability
- Worked closely with designer to develop websites based on comps

JLA Real Estate Group, Riverside, CA - Freelance Designer

December 2011 - January 2012

Responsibilities:

- Performed graphic design modifications to logo designs and designing branding material.
- Modified logo designs to work with the in-office mail application, as per the client request

The Art Institute of California, San Bernardino, CA - Peer Tutor, Library December 2009 - September 2011

Responsibilities:

- Tutored multiple students in subjects ranging from math and computer basics to fundamentals of programming and object oriented programming
- Maintained the library website and assisted with the day to day tasks of the library

Think Tank Designs, Chino Hills, CA - Webmaster Intern

October 2010 - December 2010

Responsibilities:

- Maintained and manipulated content within Joomla
- Created and edited wireframes for the client
- Created clickable mockups and HTML, CSS roughs from PSD
- Made minor adjustments to sites, as per the client request

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science, Web Design and Interactive Media - The Art Institute of California - Inland Empire, San Bernardino, CA

With Honors GPA 3.5+

September 2011

General Education, Webmaster Certification - Riverside Community College, Riverside, CA

December 2008